A Finding Aid to the Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman Papers, circa 1930s-2006, bulk 1942-2005, in the Archives of American Art AAA.koppchai
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 2004; 1937-1971; Series 9; 0.25 Linear feet Box 3
  Printed material can be found in all the series with the exception of Series 10: Artwork, and Series 11: Sketchbooks.
  Files are arranged by format and then filed in chronological order.
  - Chaim Koppelman Writings and Prints, Expressions James Madison High School, 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, James Madison High School, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters - United States Army Corp., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 2004; 1957-1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Artwork, 1933-1949; 1980-2000; Series 10; 3 Folders Box 3
  Sketches, in ink, pen, and watercolors depict figure and animal studies. A file of illustrated letters was found with the artwork and includes handmade holiday cards by Chaim Koppelman.
  Artwork can also be found in Series 1: Correspondence, Series 3: Writings and Notes, and Series 5: Teaching Files.
  Artwork is arranged by format and thereafter filed in chronological order.
  - Sketches by Chaim Koppelman, 1933-1949; 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 21-23)
  - Illustrated Letters by Chaim Koppelman, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Sketchbooks, 1944-2005; Series 11; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 3-4
  This series contains 20 annotated sketchbooks by Chaim Koppelman and an annotated sketchbook by Dorothy Koppelman. Sketches are in pen, pencil, ink, and watercolors, depicting portrait studies, figures, animals, objects, and landscapes.
  Sketchbooks are arranged in chronological order.
  - By Chaim Koppelman (Box 3)
    - Sketchbook 1, 1944-1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Sketchbook 2, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Sketchbook 3, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Sketchbook 4, 1950-1999 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Sketchbooks 5-8, 1961-1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Sketchbook 9, 1976-1988 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Sketchbooks 10-11, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Sketchbooks 12-13, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Sketchbooks 14-16, 1986-2001 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Sketchbooks 17-18, 1994-2005 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Sketchbook 19, 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - By Dorothy Koppelman (Box 4)
    - Sketchbook, 1949-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Photographs, 1930s-circa 2004; Series 12; 0.25 Linear feet Box 4
  Loose photographs are of Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman, their daughter, Ann, and other family members; also included are many snapshots of Chaim Koppelman, his army buddies, and acquaintances taken when he was in the army.
  There are four photograph albums. Two albums contain photographs and snapshots of Chaim during World War II, Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman in their studio, at exhibition installations and other events with friends and colleagues. Included are snapshots of Louis and Regina Dienes, Gerson Lieber, James Mellon, Bernard Olshan, Joseph Solman, and Theodoros Stamos. Of interest are photographs of Chaim Koppelman's sculptures and paintings completed while serving in the army. Also found are photographs of Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman with members of the Terrain Gallery in their living space at 16 West 20th Street in New York City. Interspersed among the album pages are scattered printed materials.
  Two photograph albums contain photographs of Chaim Koppelman's artwork.
  Photographs are arranged in chronological order. One photograph album was dismantled.
  - Photographs of Friends, 1940s (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - World War II Photographs of Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman and French Friends, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photograph Album 1: Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman in the Studio and at Exhibition Openings and Events with Colleagues (Dismantled), 1930s; 1942-1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photograph Album 2: Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman and Colleagues, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Photograph Albums 3-4: Chaim Koppelman Artwork, circa 2004 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)